# Ana García del Molino, PhD

I specialize in multimedia content analysis and understanding for tasks such as classification, personalization, risk detection and video summarization.

After a decade in Asia, my next adventure shall be back in Barcelona. But not before an exciting overlanding road trip across central Asia!

⊕ garciadelmolino.github.io

♀ GarciaDelMolino

☑ a.g.delmolino@gmail.com

**%** (+65) 8602 1449

**©** (+34) 675288835

# **Professional Experience**



⊕ ByteDance - TikTok, Singapore

Sept 2020-Today

① Computer Vision Scientist

Content Understanding for TikTok services. ML Ops to support both Ecology and Business Integrity. Mentoring of engineering interns and co-supervision of PhD candidates.

Technical counterpart for TikTok Live products and Business Role - Owner of content tagging services in TikTok Live: Integrity to define vision and deploy new features.

### Main Responsabilities:

- Technical lead for code development and operations of online real-time services.
- Responsible for code development, release, and maintenance
- Responsible for deployment high availability and fast response during outages.
- Point of contact for the infrastructure team to ensure smooth integration with new platform releases.
- Continuous communication with upstream teams to ensure data readiness in fast-paced environments
- Creation of reusable artifacts to enable fast deployments and new feature adoptions
- Model performance reporting with real-time dashboards for effective communication with stakeholders.

- Continuous improvement of the model design, training and benchmarking to increase recall by at least 5-10% with a target of
- Optimization of processes for data collection and labeling, resulting in the daily selection of 50k labeling tasks with a ~95% positive ratio.
- Automated model iteration, resulting in improved performance for critical business requirements, increasing F1 score from 70% to 95%.

Role - Owner of industry detection for Business Integrity:

- Model design, training and benchmarking to support new business requirements. Accuracy >75% for 800+ industries.
- Data cleaning, deduplication and aggregation across multiple sources, implementing a weekly automated collection of ~10k relevant training samples from the platform's moderation teams.
- Reusability of classification services to be used for risk moderation. Maintain low censor rate of ~1% ensuring over 95% precision for prohibited ad detection.

Multimodal Classification · ML Ops · Real-Time Services · Async Processes and Development · Data Analytics and Dashboarding · Scheduled Data Processing

 $Python \cdot TensorFlow \cdot PyTorch \cdot HSQL \cdot PySpark \cdot Golang \cdot Redis \cdot Kafka \cdot JavaScript$ 



O BIGO Tech., Singapore

<sup>△</sup> April 2019-Aug 2020

© Sr. Al Algorithm Engineer

DCNNs to predict PCA parameters for graphic 3D modeling.

GANs for face expression manipulation.

DCNN-based autoencoders and U-Nets for image and video refinement and style transfer.

 $\mathsf{VAE} \cdot \mathsf{GAN} \cdot \mathsf{Face} \ \mathsf{Landmark} \ \mathsf{Detection} \ \mathsf{and} \ \mathsf{Tracking} \cdot \mathsf{Style}$ Transfer · 3D Rendering

Python · TensorFlow · PyTorch · C# · Blender

## 2014-March 2019

① Ph.D. Candidate

△ Supervised by Joo-Hwee Lim

Visual Understanding and Personalization for an Optimal Recollection Experience

- abla Modeling of lifelog photo-stream sequences using LSTM networks, to detect daily activities and learn associations between life events.
- $\Box$  Use of conditional random fields and probabilistic inference for interactive video summarization with diversity and query-driven objectives.
- Use of image quality analysis and semantic retrieval techniques for querybased lifelog summarization.

 $Object\ Classification \cdot Activity\ Recognition \cdot Facial\ Recognition \cdot Transfer\ Learning \cdot Spatio-Temporal$ Learning with LSTM · Episodic Memory

MATLAB · Caffe · Python · TensorFlow · C++ · Prototyping

⊚ gifs.com, Zurich

**gifs.com** □ Summer 2017

① Research Consultant

Use of a deep ranking model with personalizable input to customize the highlight detection in videos.

Action Classification · Recommendation Systems · Pattern Recognition · Action Understanding

Python · TensorFlow · DataFrames · SQL · Prototyping

National Inst. of Informatics, Tokyo

₿ 2013

① Research Intern

Extension of the Bag of Words instance search technique by geometric coding and quantization error compensation.

Obtect Recognition and Retrieval · SURF & SIFT Descriptors · Hamming Embedding · Bag of Words

MATLAB · C++ · OpenCV

## **Education and Languages**

### PhD. in Cognitive Systems and Visual Computing

BSc. and MSc. in Telecomm Engineering

₿ 2008-2013

○ TelecommBCN (ETSETB)

Native Native







School of Computer Science and Engineering ₿ 2015-2019

### Honors and Awards



Obra Social "La Caixa" 📋 2014

Private fellowship to support postgraduate studies in North America and Asia-Pacific.



SINGA Scholarship # 2015

Award given by A\*STAR to international students to pursue their PhD at a Singapore University.

## **Publications**

- 🗎 Qianli Xu, Fen Fang, Ana Garcia del Molino, Vigneshwaran Subbaraju, and Joo-Hwee Lim. 2021. Predicting Event Memorability from Contextual Visual Semantics. In Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems.
- 🗎 Ana Garcia del Molino, Joo-Hwee Lim, and Ah-Hwee Tan. 2018. Predicting Visual Context for Unsupervised Event Segmentation in Continuous Photo-streams. In Proceedings of the 26th ACM international conference on Multimedia (MM '18).
- 🗎 Ana Garcia del Molino and Michael Gygli. 2018. PHD-GIFs: Personalized Highlight Detection for Automatic GIF Creation. In Proceedings of the 26th ACM international conference on Multimedia (MM '18).
- 🗎 Ana Garcia del Molino, Xavier Boix, Joo-Hwee Lim, and Ah-Hwee Tan. 2017. Active Video Summarization: Customized Summaries via Online Interaction with the User. In AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence.
- 🗎 Ana Garcia del Molino, Cheston Tan, Joo-Hwee Lim, and Ah-Hwee Tan. 2017. Summarization of Egocentric Videos: A Comprehensive Survey. In IEEE Transactions on Human-Machine Systems, 47(1).
- 🗎 Ana Garcia del Molino, Bappaditya Mandal, Jie Lin, Joo Hwee Lim, Vigneshwaran Subbaraju, Vijay Chandrasekhar. 2017. VC-I2R@ ImageCLEF2017: Ensemble of Deep Learned Features for Lifelog Video Summarization. In CLEF working notes.
- 🗎 Qianli Xu, Vigneshwaran Subbaraju, Ana Garcia del Molino, Jie Lin, Fen Fang, Joo-Hwee Lim, Liyuan Li, Vijay Chandrasekhar. 2017. Visualizing Personal Lifelog Data for Deeper Insights at the NTCIR-13 Lifelog-2 Task.
- 🗎 Jie Lin, Ana Garcia del Molino, Qianli Xu, Fen Fang, Vigneshwaran Subbaraju, Joo-Hwee Lim, Liyuan Li, Vijay Chandrasekhar. 2017. VCI2R at the NTCIR-13 Lifelog-2 Lifelog Semantic Access Task.
- 🗎 Ana Garcia del Molino, Qianli Xu, Joo-Hwee Lim. 2016. Describing lifelogs with convolutional neural networks: A comparative study. In Proceedings of the first Workshop on Lifelogging Tools and Applications.
- 🗎 Ana Garcia del Molino. 2016. First Person View Video Summarization Subject to the User Needs. In Proceedings of the 24th ACM international conference on Multimedia (MM'16).
- 🗎 Ana Garcia del Molino, Bappaditya Mandal, Liyuan Li, Lim Joo Hwee. 2015. Organizing and retrieving episodic memories from first person view. In IEEE International Conference on Multimedia & Expo Workshops (ICMEW).

(Check all my publications in my Scholar profile)